Now that we've gone through binding a bit, let's talk
about controllers.
So let's take this data from this ng-model and kind of
extract it out into a controller which will provide
the data for us.
So we'll take this entire code block here and we'll wrap it
in a div, and to ng-controller, and we'll just
call this our FirstCtrl.
Now you can see that everything inside this div is
going to have the scope of that controller.
So let's go ahead and delete that ng-model data.message, so
we have nothing providing that data message to our bound
expression.
So if we set up our script, we'll just say main.js is a
file and create it.
And let's define something called first controller.
FirstCtrl.
And from here, what happens is you pass in the $scope, and
that $scope is again related to these elements and
everything contained inside of there.
It's kind of the scope of what can go on in this controller.
And inside that $scope we'll create a model, which we've
just called data so far.
And we'll say the message is hello.
So if we refresh, we can see we're now using the same
data.message, but now we're getting the hello from the
controller in here.
So if we did the panel again and we refresh from there, you
can see we create the panel.
But now the data's being provided from
a JavaScript file.
So you can write to your behaviors and everything
inside of here instead of just trying to relate everything to
some sort of user input.
So in your controller you can use the service calls or other
things to get data to push into your view.
So that's the basics of a controller and